CURRICULUM VITAE



Toutsop Dongmo Jordan

Full Stack Web Developer

Born on 9 March 1999 in Yaoundé Buea, South West, Cameroon

I am a highly efficient and reliable professional who possesses a broad skill set for web application development. I focus on creating code that is easy to read, maintain, and test to optimize the developers experience and the apps themselves.

Languages Mastered: Html, Css, Javascript, Nodejs, Angular 8, Django, TypeScript, Php, Swagger, Mysql, PostgreSql, Apache, Git, Gitlab, Cisco packet tracer, Postman, Figma, Mikro C, Ms office, Spring-boot.



Accounts

https://github.com/ToutsopDongmoJordan21

toutsopjordan1999@gmail.com



Spoken Languages | Nationality

| Phone Number

English French | Cameroonian | (+237) 699028439/ 681409045



Skills and Abilities

Optimist, Visionary, Open-minded, Focused, Ambitious.

Professional experience

Front-end Developer

Freelancer, Cameroon

August 2022 - October 2022

- > Designing and implementing multiple software for individuals.
- > Using continuous integration and continuous delivery to ship clean, well-tested code to production on a regular basis.
- > Deployment of the software into firebase host. This is the link (https://westerncare2-6d06a.web.app/).

Technologies: Angular 14, FireBase, Git.

Front-end Developer

Floraison, Cameroon

Hackhaton | 25March - 30March

- Updating the web application apps design to match the existing Android apps design using the framework Angular 8.
- > Make the connection with the existing Firebase database.
- > Develops and integrate the functionalities of the apps.

The application is on play Store, his name is floraison.

Full Stack Developer

Advanced -IT, Cameroon Full -time | September 2020 - February 2021

- Designing, implementing, and maintaining back-end code, database schema, APIs, and models. Using Figma Design components to build the web interface of a Car rent and selling systems that provides available cars for users depending of its localization.
- Building and managing custom components.
- Collaborating with teammates to understand user and business requirements while developing new features and improving existing ones and Testing The API.

Technologies: Spring-boot, Mysql, Angular, Gitlab, Figma, Postman, Swagger, Unit Testing.

Front-end Developer

Zepstra Limited, Novazen SARL | Internship | August 2019 - November 2019 | Internship | August 2015 - November 2015

- > Built the app architecture and designed system components and Building Figma Design components to build the front-end application of Invoice web application. Connection of the system with Mysql database.
- > Maintenance of computer component in the structure.

Technologies: Angular 8, Mysql, Git, Javascript, Bootstrap.

Education

Master's degree in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering)	2021 – now
University of Buea, Buea– Cameroon	
Bachelor's degree in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering)	2017 – 2021
University of Buea, Buea– Cameroon	
Baccalaureat série TI (Technologie de l'information)	2014 – 2017
College Prive Laic Fleming, Yaounde – Cameroon	
BEPC (Brevet d'étude du premier cycle) Bilingue	2010 – 2014
College Prive Laic Fleming , Yaounde - Cameroon	